Data File #1

Data file name- cleaned_HGMAPS.csv

Studies incorporated- Hunt Study (Full name: "Hair Mercury Level is Associated with Anemia and Micronutrient Status in 
Children Living Near Artisanal and Small-Scale Gold Mining in the Peruvian Amazon"),
Interoceanic Highway Study (Full name: "Population-based dietary exposure to mercury through fish consumption in the Southern Peruvian Amazon"),
RioMDD Study/ Also calleed River Study (Full name: "River transport of mercury
from artisanal and small-scale gold mining and risks for dietary mercury exposure in Madre de Dios, Peru")

Sample type- Human hair

Hunt Study Description- N = 3,128 study participants received hemoglobin testing and N = 2,308 study participants received hair total mercury testing; 
N = 2,237 received both tests. 
The study, we focused on children < 12. Here, we report analysis of total hair mercury content, hemoglobin,
and serum micronutrient levels in children < 12 years of age (N = 83) near ASGM in the Peruvian Amazon. 

Sample type- Human hair

Interoceanic Highway Study Description- Hair samples and household demographic surveys, including a module on fish consumption, 
were collected from 723 participants across 46 communities within 10 km of the Interoceanic Highway in MDD. 

Sample types- suspended particles, sediment, fish

RioMDD/River Study- This research examined the spatial distribution and transport of mercury through the Madre de Dios River with distance from ASGM activity.  
River sediment, suspended solids from the water column, 
and fish samples were collected in 2013 at 62 sites near 17 communities over a 560 km stretch of the Madre de Dios River and its major tributaries.


Data File #2

Data File name- suspendedparticles_final.csv

Sample type- Suspended particles in water, sediment, fish

Study incorporated- River study (Full name: "River transport of mercury from artisanal and small-scale gold mining 
and risks for dietary mercury exposure in Madre de Dios, Peru")

River Study Description- This research examined the spatial distribution and transport of mercury through the Madre de Dios River with distance from ASGM activity.  
River sediment, suspended solids from the water column, 
and fish samples were collected in 2013 at 62 sites near 17 communities over a 560 km stretch of the Madre de Dios River and its major tributaries.


Data File #3 

Data file name- sediment_analysis_final.csv

Sample type- Sediment, suspended particles, fish 

Study incorporated- Study incorporated- River study (Full name: "River transport of mercury from artisanal and small-scale gold mining 
and risks for dietary mercury exposure in Madre de Dios, Peru")

River Study Description- ""


Data File #4

Data file name- FishAnalysisLagCategories_final.csv

Sample type- Fish

Study incorporated- El Nino Study (Full name: "Impact of El Niño on Environmental Mercury in Madre de Dios, Peru")

El Nino Study Description- This is one of the first studies to investigate the impact of El Niño on environmental mercury
concentrations. This study found that El Niño has a large effect in increasing fish tissue mercury
concentrations. 






